亲爱的 要我把车开出去吗
Honey, do you need me to move the car?
不 不用 我能行
No, it's nothing. I'm alright
不 铁十字给我力量 它要栽了
Oh no! Iron cross, she's going down
当心 菲尔
Oh god! Phil...
-你没事吧 -没事
- You okay? - Yes. I am.
我没事
I am okay.
亲爱的 我们为什么要留着这辆车
Honey, why do we keep this car?
这车老经典了
It's a classic!
不 它只是空占地方
No, it just sits here.
安全带也坏了
And the seatbelts don't work.
门也卡 还漏油
The doors stick. It leaks fluids.
我们也十年没给它加过油了
We haven't put fluids in it in 10 years.
我会把这些毛病都修好
Well, I'm gonna fix all that anyway.
然后 送给海莉
And then, uh, it's gonna be Haley's car.
我才不要给海莉
Oh, we're not giving this car to Haley.
车后座都宽得可以放床垫了
It's way too easy to fit a mattress in the back.
当年这车可是我们的洞房啊
Remember?
要命了 这车必须卖
Oh, no. We're selling it.
什么
What?!
除非你觉得你卖不出
Unless you don't think you can.
-此话当真 -是的
- Really? - Yeah.
-确定当真 -绝对当真
- Seriously? - You can't.
你确定我卖不掉
You honestly think that's gonna work?
就是卖不掉
You can't sell it.
话说
You know what?
你怎么羞辱我都可以
You can insult a lot of things about me...
发型啊 声音啊 平衡板游戏啥的
My hair, my voice, my balance-board exercises...
就是不要羞辱我强大的销售能力
But don't insult my selling.
过分了哈
That crosses a line.
过在哪里 你瞧不见?
What line? Oh, you don't see it?
因为我以光速给它卖了
That's 'cause I just sold it.
当这个美黑小星星声称
While the spray-tanned starlet claims
自己有六个星期没嗑药时 知情者爆料道
to be six weeks sober, sources down under say:
她就像一个嗑药过量的袋鼠一样
She has been bar-hopping
蹦啊跳啊混迹于酒吧
like a coked-up kangaroo."
爹地给你读什么呢
Ah, what's daddy reading to you?
如果还要我再读一次
If I have to read "the very hungry caterpillar"
《饥肠辘辘的毛毛虫》 我会抓狂的
One more time, I will snap.
-哪有那么差劲啊 -别逼人家
- oh, it's not that bad. - I will snap!
那啥 我把工具箱拿到外面了
So, um, I laid the toolbox outside,
所有的材料也都准备好了
And all the supplies are ready,
可以开工了
And I think we are good to go!
好极了
Terrific.
你不打算换身工人套装吗
Aren't you gonna change into a working man's outfit?
不用了
No, I'm good,
况且我不觉得工人管它叫"套装"
And I don't think workmen really call them "outfits."
我们要给莉莉建一座公主城堡
We are building a princess castle for Lily.
这是每个父亲都想给他女儿建的
Uh, it's something every father wants to be able to do for his daughter.
并且 我把自己幻想成
You know, and I fancy myself
这个城堡的设计师
as a bit of a castle designer.
我画了一些草图
I have done a few sketches.
那些以备后用 这样我们就能用组装套件
Which we have archived so we can use the kit.
-对 -套件
- Mm, yeah. - The kit.
套件 我们夫妇一条心一起做
Uh, the kit. Which, uh, we're gonna do together.
要跟米奇尔一起做这个还不如杀了我
I am petrified to do this with Mitchell.
他大学的时候做过几个戏剧的布景什么的
He built a couple of theater sets in college or something,
就以为自己是建筑帝了
And now he thinks he knows everything about building.
但他根本不搭边
Well, he doesn't.
每次我们家要做改造
Every home-improvement project that we've undertaken.
都让人好想死好想死
Has been a near-death experience.
做开胃菜 然后...
Make the appetizers. And then we'll be...
如果真出了啥意外 我希望他一下解决了我
If an accident does happen, I hope he kills me...
因为我觉得我不会是个乐观向上的残障人士
Because I don't think I would be a very inspiring disabled person.
亲爱滴 放亲松
Honey, relax.
她还没来
She's not here yet.
你最好蛋定一下 别猴急猴急的
You might want to play it a little cooler.
要不会把你女朋友吓跑的
You don't want to scare off your girlfriend.
她才不是我女朋友
She's not my girlfriend!
她只是过来跟我一起研究蚕的生命周期
She's just coming over to study the life cycle of silkworms.
嗷 她到了
Oh. She's here.
她到了 那啥 我头发不乱吧
She's here! okay, how's my hair?
是谁说只是朋友来着
I thought it was just a friend.
我可听到了
I heard that.
我故意的
I wasn't whispering.
曼尼去开门 让她感受什么叫宾至如归
Manny, open the door. Make her feel welcome.
凯莉 早上好
Kelly! Good morning.
欢迎你来我家
Uh, I'm glad you're here.
这是我妈
Um, this is my Mom.
很高兴认识你哦
Nice to meet you!
在我们的文化里
In my culture,
母亲都灰常粘儿子
mothers are very clingy to their sons.
其实呢 哥伦比亚妇女死亡的首要原因
In fact, the leading cause of death among Colombian women
就是她们的儿子要结婚
is when their sons get married.
但是我不会这样
But I'm not like that.
我只要曼尼高兴就好哩
I just want my Manny to be happy.
曼尼 叫你的朋友凯莉吃肉卷馅饼
Manny, why don't you give your friend Kelly an empanada?
不了 谢谢
Oh, no, thank you.
我尽量避免摄入反式脂肪
I try to stay away from trans fats.
哎呀呀 就吃一个没啥滴啦
Oh, I'm sure one won't make a difference.
这是曼尼的最爱哟
They're Manny's favorite!
我 我也不要吃反式脂肪了
I... think I'm going to stop eating trans fats, too.
妈 这是在哪拍的
Mom? When was this from?
这是我跟你爸去看玫瑰杯的时候拍的
Oh... That's the year your dad and I went to the rose bowl.
-那场老精彩了 -是啊
- Incredible game. - Yeah.
妈 你看起来真美
Mom, you look really pretty.
谢谢你 宝贝儿
Thank you, sweetheart.
那后来怎么回事
So, what happened?
小卢克 人人都会变老嘛
Well, Lukey, everyone gets older.
即便你妈的风采不再
Just 'cause parts of your mom aren't what they used to be,
也不代表...
it doesn't meam...
我是想问比赛后来怎么样了
I mean, what happened in the game?
我们输给了宾州队
We got our butts kicked by Penn state.
但是游行非常棒
The parade was awesome, though.
是安吉拉·兰斯伯里担任司仪
Angela Lansbury was the grand marshal.
"美好的记忆" 她写道
"Good time," she wrote.
行了 继续收拾
Okay, come on, guys. Let's get back to it.
堆着这么多东西没人会买的
No one's gonna buy this heap looking this way.
恶 妈妈 垃圾丢哪边
Hey, mom, which one is the garbage can?
丢...
Um, it...
乖乖 这个不能丢
Honey, you can't throw that away.
这是小毯毯
It's blankety.
可它有够恶心
It's disgusting.
怎么会 亲爱的 你以前可喜欢它了
No, sweetie, you loved blankety.
你上哪儿都要带着它
You wouldn't go anywhere without him.
哈 直到卢克吐在上面
Yeah, until Luke threw up on it.
哈哈
Yeah.
我年轻的时候老吐
I used to throw up all the time.
还记得呕吐桶桶吗
Remember buckety?
看这个
Oh, look at this.
这是什么
What is that?
那天咱们去海边
We went to the beach one day,
卢克玩得很开心
and Luke had such a good time.
所以他要带一罐阳光回家
That he wanted to being home a jar of sunshine.
这样他就能永远记着了
So he could always remember it.
还记得吗 亲爱的
Do you remember, honey?
不 不不 别 别打开
Oh, no... no, no, don't... don't open it.
你真以为你把阳光收进罐子里了
You really think you trapped sunshine in there?
我现在通知你们
I'm just letting you know now,
你们死了之后我绝对不会管他的
I'm not taking care of him when you guys die.
别说了 这样做很可爱的
Stop. It's sweet.
还热热的好吧
Still feels hot.
刚看车那家伙来电话了
Hey! It's that guy who came by earlier.
貌似很想买
He was really interested.
他叫啥来着 快告诉我
What was his name? Shoot!
做销售千万不能忘记客户姓名
Well, you can't be in sales and not remember people's names.
所以我用"迷你联想"来帮助记忆
That's why I like to use what they call "minimonic" devices.
这是帮助记忆的小诀窍
They're little tricks to help you remember.
就像那天 我认识了个家伙叫卡尔
Um, like the other day, I met this guy named Carl.
现在我或许忘了他的名字
Now, I might forget that name,
但我记得她穿着一件Grateful Dead的汗衫
But he was wearing a Grateful Dead T-shirt.
有什么乐队像Grateful Dead
What's a band like the Grateful Dead?
Phish 鱼生活在哪里
Phish. Where do fish live?
海洋
The ocean.
什么东西生长在海洋
What else lives in the ocean?
珊瑚
Coral.
你好 卡罗
Hello, "Coral".
我记得这是"助记口诀"
I think it's "mnemonic".
啊… 我觉得我没记错
I... I think I'd remember.
行吧
Okay.
老爸 你一定行的
You can do it, dad.
好吧
Okay.
他看起来像是个外国鼓手
He looked like the drummer from foreigner.
这个外国人来自法国
Now, foreigner's from France.
法国和蚂蚁押韵[英文单词读音]
France rhymes with "ants."
蚂蚁破坏了野餐
Ants ruin a picnic.
哈啰 Nick[和野餐后缀音同]
What's up, Nick?
是吗
Really?
真的吗
那太好了
Well, that's great.
随时欢迎 我们一整天都在
Yeah, no, swing by anytime. We're here all day.
谢谢
Thanks.
你猜怎么着
Guess what?
谁说哥卖不出去
You said I couldn't sell this?
你自打嘴巴了吧
Well, you're gonna be eating a humble pie.
高兴不起来了吧 真对不住了嘿
Stuffed with crow and a big side of sorry,
我给它卖了
'cause I just did.
当你的面卖出去了 叫你老否定咱爷们
In your face, girl with the negative tattoo!
亲爱的
Honey...
等等
Wait.
不
No!
有人输不起了
Whoa. Someone doesn't like to lose.
宝贝
Honey.
宝贝儿
Honey!
对不起
I'm sorry.
今早一睁眼 我还很烦那辆车
When I woke up this morning, I hated that car,
就连想起它都让我抓狂
and even thinking about it made me mad.
但是我们一起经历了这么多
But then when we were going through it,
还有那个可爱的小毯毯…
and blankety...
所有这一切 我只是
all that stuff... I just...
一想到那些美丽的日子就这样随车而逝了
The thought of that whole part of our life driving away...
我们可以留着小毯毯嘛
We can keep blankety.
但我不想...
I don't want...
看看他们
Look at them.
好像昨天他们还都只是小宝宝
Come on. A minute ago, they were babies.
今天呢 连车都会开了
And now they're driving.
然后我们也不久于人世了
And soon we'll all be dead.
打住 你咋能忽略掉死前的美好时光呢
Whoa! You're leaving out a few great minutes there.
退休啊 颐养天年啊
Retirement, old age...
超级酷的爬楼梯自动椅子啊
Cool chair that goes up the stairs.
是啊 对不起
Yeah. I'm sorry.
我不该胡思乱想
I'm... being ridiculous.
不用道歉 我就喜欢你充满着人情味
Don't apologize. I love you when you're human.
听着
Listen.
听我说
Hey! listen!
车不卖了
We don't have to sell the car.
亲爱的 当然要卖
Oh, sweetie, of course we do.
没理由要留着它
It doesn't make any sense to keep it.
那我该怎么做才能让你感觉好点
Well, what can I do to make you feel better?
什么也不用做
Nothing.
除非你给我造一台时光机
Unless you can build me a time machine.
亲爱的
Honey...
除非有人能想办法
Until someone can figure out how to keep a wormhole
阻止虫洞的倒塌
from collapsing in on itself.
否则就是痴人说梦
That's just a pipe dream.
是啊
Sure.
菲尔 想都别想 菲尔
Phil! come on back, phil.
我找到了...
Well, I found the...
我找到了射钉枪
I found the nail gun.
噢 太好了
Oh. Yay.
奇怪的是 它给裹在一条旧毛巾里
The weirdest thing... it was wrapped in an old towel
塞在盒子里 在壁橱最顶上
stuffed in a box on the top shelf of the closet.
赶紧把它放在柜台上
Well, just set it down on the counter.
小心
Heads up!
老爸 你来这干嘛
Oh, dad, what are you doing here?
我只是来还歌洛莉亚借的电锅
I'm, uh, just, uh, returning that crockpot that Gloria borrowed.
我都忘了这码事了 杰
Oh, yeah, I forgot you had that crockpot, Jay.
我们正准备给莉莉建造一座公主城堡
Well, we're just getting ready to build Lily a princess castle
如果你...
if you...
-想帮忙 -当然 没问题
- Want to help? - Yeah, sure.
只要你不介意的话 米奇尔
Oh. Well, if it's okay with you, Mitchell.
好啊 我没问题 老爸
Oh, yeah! oh, no, dad.
还记得当初我们一起做书架的时候吗
Oh, remember how much fun we had
多美好的回忆呀
when we built that bookshelf together?
那简直就像打了场越战
That was my vietnam.
我确实参加过越战
And I was in vietnam.
看看我们哦
Oh! Look at us!
我们就是工匠三兄弟
Three construction dudes!
老爸 我去给你拿几副专用手套
Dad, I'm gonna get you some workman gloves.
我有蓝色的和驼色的
I have a blue and camel.
你喜欢哪个颜色的
What's your preference?
你懂的
Surprise me.
如果我们把东西都整理到同一个笔记本上
Wouldn't it be easier
那不就轻松多了
if we had all our stuff in the same notebook?
你这么觉得
You think?
这样我们就省的总是来回翻了
I mean, we're always going back and forth.
我把我的笔记夹到你的本子上
I'll just put my things in your notebook.
好的
okay.
谁想喝巧克力奶呀
Who wants chocolate milk?
我要 妈妈
Sure, mom.
-进度如何呀 -好极了
- So how is it going? - Great!
凯莉在把她的笔记
Kelly's moving her stuff
都搬到我的本子上
into my notebook.
速度还真快啊
This is sudden.
应该的
It just felt right.
你应该这样
Oh, you know what you should do?
在巧克力奶里放一撮盐
Put a pinch of salt in the chocolate milk.
提味得多
It really brings out the flavor.
吃爆米花才用盐呢
Salt is for the popcorn.
听起来对味
That sounds good.
你不会喜欢的
You wouldn't like it.
也许我们该让曼尼自己决定
Maybe we should let Manny decide.
好滴
Okay.
给你盐
Here's the salt.
我们看他选哪个
We'll see what he likes.
天啊
Wow!
好喝翻了
That's really good!
妈妈 你试试
Try it, mom!
老娘对这无爱
I don't care for it.
其实很好喝
It was delicious.
终于把莉莉哄睡了
I finally got Lily down for a nap.
米奇尔在哪里
Where is Mitchell?
怎么能没人看着他呢
He's not supposed to be unsupervised!
没事
Don't worry.
我让他去车库给塔顶插旗子
I got him in the garage putting flags on the spires.
哦 那就好
Okay, perfect.
这样最好 省的有人受伤了
It's better that way. Nobody gets hurt.
插旗子这事儿也省了
We don't have to put flags on the spires.
是啊
Yeah.
好了 我们来盖上屋顶
All right, let's get this roof on.
应该咔嚓就扣上了
It's supposed to snap right into place.
嘿
Hey!
你干的怎么样了 电锯哥[电锯惊魂里的杀人狂]
Whatcha got going on over there, Jigsaw?
我觉得我得从吊桥开工
Well, I thought that I would get started
屋顶就归你们了 所以...
on the, uh, drawbridge while you guys worked on the roof, so...
你的旗子都插好了吗
You all done with the flags?!
当然
Yeah!
十五分钟就搞定了
Yeah, it took me like 15 minutes.
哪里像你说的那么麻烦
It was a lot easier than you made it out to be.
杰 怎么办
Do something, Jay.
米奇
Uh, Mitch?!
干嘛
Yeah.
你去弄点三明治吧
How about you make us some sandwiches?
不成 不成 我们还没完工呢
No. No, we're in the middle of this.
不是 杰的意思是说
No, I think what Jay's saying is,
你为什么不挑点螺栓来
why don't you go sort some bolts?
不用 我已经挑好了
No, I sorted the bolts.
-全部吗 -一共就六个
- All of 'em? - There were six.
你们俩不对劲啊
W... what's going on with you two?
难道 是想把我甩开不成
Are you... are you trying to get rid of me?
呃 米奇
Uh..., Mitch.
天 你们真是闲我碍事
Oh, my god. You are.
你们 居然狼狈为奸
You're... you're, like, in cahoots.
米奇尔 你一碰工具 我就害怕
Mitchell, I get scared, when you're around tools,
亲爱的 这太危险了
Honey, it's dangerous...
对你 对我
For me, for you,
对我们的花花 都是威胁
for... our roses.
孩子 他说得对
Works better this way, kid.
我是指 顺利建好城堡
I mean, castle goes right up,
没人给一切两半
Nobody gets sliced in half.
你们也太小看人了吧 我可是…
Do you know how insulting this is? I was...
我可是在歌鸟夏季剧院实习过的
I was an intern at the songbird summer playhouse.
你们以为南海仙境那出戏
Do you think that the town of Brigadoon
就嗖一下变出来了吗
just magically appeared?
当然戏里看着是这么回事 但是 那个布景
Well, in the play, it did, but...the set...
那个布景是我用这双手搭的
the set was built with these two hands!
米奇尔 米奇尔
Mitchell. Mitchell...
还有范特普庄园 艾维塔的阳台
The Von Trapp mansion, Evita's balcony...
算了 算了
Okay. Okay.
你这是要去哪
Oh, where are you going?
我要暴走了
I'm going on a walk,
哈 没错 我还能自己走
and, oh, yeah, I can still do that by myself.
看着嘿 哦 好害怕会摔倒哦
Watch. Oh, I hope I don't get hurt.
哦 妈呀 谁这么缺德放个门柱在这儿
Oh, god, who put that doorjamb there?
害我没看见
I didn't see it.
直接撞上去了
I ran right into it.
哎呀 糟糕 绊着了 走路好难的说
Oh, no, I tripped! Walking is so hard!
刚才那下可不像是故意的
That one didn't look like it was on purpose.
就是故意的
It was!
还有几步路
Just a few more steps.
对不起!
Oh, sorry!
有台阶 有台阶 对不起
Step! Step! Sorry!
-菲尔 -对不起 对不起
- Phil?! - Sorry, sorry.
这一跤绝对值
It's gonna be worth it.
绝对不值
No, it's not.
别听她瞎说
Don't listen to her.
开...
And...
-嗷 嗷 嗷 -对不起 不要乱动
- Ow. Ow. Ow! - Sorry. Don't struggle.
不要乱动
Stop struggling.
好惊喜啊 我们的车
Great. It's our car.
不只是车哦 孩子们
Not a car. Kids?
"时" 什么
"ti... " what?
今天晚上 克莱尔·邓菲 我们把时钟拨回
Tonight, Claire Dunphy, we are turning back the clock
那纯真年代...
to a simpler time...
当年那个咱一家挤在旅行车里
when families piled into their station wagons,
捎上一些汉堡
picked up some burgers,
去郊外野餐的日子
and went on a picnic up to granger point.
亲爱的 没必要吧
Honey, we don't have to do this.
她说得对
Listen to her.
不啊 会很好玩的 我跟那个
No, it's gonna be great. I talked to...
法国 蚂蚁 野餐%￥%@&*...
France, ants, picnic...
尼克说了 他明天才来取车
Nick, and he's not picking up the car till tomorrow.
我们还能来一次家庭大聚会
We have one more night of family fun!
能有啥意思
What's gonna be fun about it?
谁说不是
Listen to him
-啥都有意思 -啥也没意思
- Only everything. - Only nothing.
好了 小朋友们
Okay, kids, you know what?
你们老爹要做好人好事
Your father is trying to do something nice,
你们少抱怨点儿多好
so I would appreciate it if you would stop your whining
赶紧上车
and just get in the car.
屡试不爽
Still does it!
啊哈
Oh, my!
快点 快点进去
Come on, get in, get in!
我不得不说 他得学会释怀
I'm just saying, the kid's gotta learn to let things go.
这对米奇尔是个敏感话题
Well, this is a touchy subject for Mitchell.
他就想体现男子汉的一面 就像咱俩
He wants to feel like a regular joe, like you and I.
哦 不好意思
Oh, pardonnez-moi.
比起普通香槟 我更倾向于第戎香槟
I prefer the champagne Dijon to the standard yellow.
要证明自己是纯爷们 方法很多 你懂的
You know, there are a few areas that define us as men,
比如运动健身 还有木工啥的
like sports and construction.
米奇尔只是想证明自个是
Mitchell just wants to feel like he's...
爷们俱乐部中的一员
part of the man club.
你俩不就那地儿认识的
Isn't that where you guys met?
我知道你这开玩笑是因为基佬氛围让你不适
I know you're making a joke because you're uncomfortable,
我当没听见
so I'll let it slide.
我们在性派对上认识的
and we met at an orgy.
淡定
Come on.
我就觉得那啥太疯狂了 仅此而已
I just think it's crazy, that's all.
他拿不稳锤子又怎么着
So what if he can't swing a hammer?
要看他好的一面啊
Look at all he has done.
法律学校出身 事业蒸蒸日上 还能养家糊口
Law school, great career, providing for his family.
未必还不够爷们
That's manly, too, isn't it?
传统意义上很不错了
I mean, the classical sense.
对 是 同样我觉得
Well, yes, I mean, I think it also takes a big man
辞去音乐老师的工作回家养孩子
to quit his career as a music teacher
也是爷们所为
and raise a child.
你也很爷们 小卡
You're a man, too, Cam.
谢谢 杰
Thank you, Jay.
等等 忘了装饰 再爷们
Wait. Garnish. We're men...
也要讲究啦
not cavemen.
我爷爷的爷爷的爷爷
My great-great-grandfather
参与过建造布鲁克林大桥
helped build the Brooklyn bridge.
我听说在他有生之年里
And I heard that, until the day he died,
每每经过大桥 一股自豪感便油然而生
every time he passed it, he was filled with such pride.
他会说 这桥有我一份功劳
He'd say, "there's a little bit of me in that bridge."
我知道自己不手巧
I know that I'm not the handiest guy,
但我是男人嘛
but I'm still a man,
我只希望能望向自家后院深情道出…
and I want to be able to look out into my yard and say...
这公主城堡有我一份功劳
"there's a little bit of me in that princess castle."
哦 不 不要啊
Oh, no. No. No, no, no. No.
不要啊
No. Oh, no.
嘿 妈妈
Hey, mom.
凯莉的父母马上就要来了
Kelly's parents are on their way.
她邀请我和他们一起吃饭看电影
She invited me to go out to dinner and a movie with them.
你批准吗
Is that okay?
哦 可是...
Oh, but...
不是说好咱俩去看电影吗
I thought that you and I were going to the movies tonight.
就是希亚·拉博夫演的那个呀
You know, to see that one with Shia Labeouf.
我们可以改天晚上去看呀
Well, maybe we can go to the movie another night.
怎么了
W... what's wrong?
没事啦
Oh, nothing.
小心脏好难受
Just my heart.
好呀 告我去呀
Okay, sue me.
我就是一个哥伦比亚妈妈
I am a Colombian mother.
我才不会让他犯错误
I'm not gonna let him make a mistake
影响我滴一生
that is gonna affect him for the rest of my life!
他滴一生
His life!
曼尼
Manny,
我觉得是时候谈谈凯莉的问题了
I think we should talk about this Kelly girl.
她是不是巨好
Isn't she great?
我觉得她对我有意思
I think she really likes me.
她怎么可能会对你没意思呢 当然啦
Why wouldn't she like you, baby? Of course.
去吧 玩开心呀
Go. Have fun.
我决定穿那件酒红色西装
I'm gonna wear my burgundy dinner jacket.
穿去吧
Of course you are.
我觉得应该先道歉
I say we apologize
然后按照他的意思一起把城堡修好
and just finish the castle together like he wanted.
-你有把射钉枪藏好吧 -必须的
- Did you hide the nail gun? - Absolutely.
问题是 上回你也这么说来着
'cause, I mean, you said that before.
不是 我...
No, I...
哦 天啊 已经盖好了
Oh, my gosh. It's finished.
什么情况 米奇尔干的吗
What the hell? Mitchell did that?
对啊 对啊 就是米奇尔干的
Yes. Yes, Mitchell did it.
傻眼了吧 贱人们
Who's the bitch now, bitches?
亲爱的 真漂亮
Honey, it looks beautiful!
当然啦 你们两个在里面
Well, yeah, because when you two were inside
搞家家酒的时候 我一人在这里
enjoying your little tea party, I was out here...
辛苦干活
out here getting stuff done.
我错了
I'm sorry.
我们不该小看你
We shouldn't have underestimated you.
看出来他被困在里面了吧
You know he's stuck in there, right?
太明显了
Oh, yeah.
嘿 儿子 我和小卡要去喝点冰啤酒
Uh, hey, kid, Cam and I are gonna go crack a couple cold ones.
你要不要一起啊
You want to join us?
不用了
No, no, you know what?
我就留下把剩下的活做完
I'm just gonna stay here and get some stuff done,
你们两位小姐进去喝点淡啤吧
but you... you two ladies enjoy your light beers.
你怎么知道我们要喝淡啤
How do you know we're having light beers?
家里只有淡啤
We only have light beers.
听着
So, well, listen.
-锤子在这里 -放这儿干嘛 我又不用
- Here is a hammer. - I don't need it. I don't need it, though.
-这个是螺丝刀 -我又用不着
- And this is a screwdriver. - But I'm not gonna use it.
你想喝酒就进来
And you just come on in whenever you want to.
马上就… 来
I'll be in at... yeah.
你确定不用把他弄出来
You sure we shouldn't get him out of there?
不用 否则他永远不会原谅我们的
No. He would never forgive us.
你儿子自尊心强着呢
He's a very proud man, your son.
鸟 鸟
Bird! Bird!
有鸟 天啊啊啊
Bird! ah, oh, my god! oh, my god!
我现在可自豪的很啊
Yeah, I'm pretty proud of myself right now.
我的妈呀
Ohh! oh, my god!
淡定
Calm down.
卢克 宝贝 慢点吃
Luke, honey, slow down.
没人跟你抢
No one's gonna take your food away.
这地方变化可真大啊
Wow, this place has really changed.
光阴荏苒啊
Time marches on, huh?
看到下面那家星巴克了吗
See that Starbucks down there?
你们知道那儿原来是什么吗
You know what that used to be?
橘子园吗
An orange grove?
不对 是汉堡王
No, a Burger King.
还能看到当时的建筑风格
You can still see some of the architecture.
谢谢你 做这些
Thank you... for this.
我真的感觉好多了
I really do feel better already.
克莱尔 美丽的日子一直都在
You can go home again, Claire.
亲爱的
Oh, sweetie.
我胃疼
My stomach hurts.
卢克 宝贝 叫你别吃那么快
Luke, honey, I told you not to eat so fast.
坐回去休息一下就没事的
Just sit back, relax. You're gonna be fine.
-有蜘蛛 -海莉
- Ew! Spider! - Haley!
-海莉 -海莉 宝贝
-Haley! - Haley, honey,
你踩住你爸的安全带了
you're standing on the back of daddy's seatbelt!
偶滴神啊 又能呼吸了
Oh, soft cheeses, I can breathe again.
等等 蜘蛛到哪儿去了
Wait. Where'd the spider go?
我得透透气
I really need some air.
好吧 艾丽克斯 把车窗摇下来
Okay, Alex, lower your window.
我摇不动 它卡住了
I can't. It's stuck.
我把这事给忘了
I forgot about that.
不准吐我身上
Don't you throw up on me.
别把他推给我
Ohh. Don't point him at me!
在这儿 我把这个打开… 海莉
Here, I'll turn on the... Haley!!
亲爱的 我想这应该是暖气
Oh! Oh, honey, I think that's the heat.
喷我嘴里了
It's in my mouth.
我要吐了
It's happening!
好吧 拿个袋子
okay, grab a bag!
晕 这袋子一股洋葱味
Oh, gosh, it smells like onions!
我的安全带卡住了
My seatbelt's stuck!
我来帮你
I'll help you.
天啊
oh, my god!
蜘蛛
Spider!
海莉
Haley!!
天啊 他要吐了 妈
Oh, god, he's gonna blow, mom!
我要小桶桶
I need buckety!
好吧 所有人都下车
Okay, everybody get out of the car!
我们这边的门打不开
Our doors don't open!
交给我们
We got ya.
慢则稳 稳则快
Slow is smooth, and smooth is fast!
出来 出来
Get out, get out.
邓菲家的 慢则稳 稳则快
Slow is smooth, and smooth is fast, Dunphys!
轻且慢
Nice and easy!
慢则稳 稳则快
Slow is smooth, and smooth is fast.
别看他
Don't look at him!
小心恶心到
He's just gonna make you feel sick!
我看到了 我看到了 我看到了
Oh, I looked, I looked, I looked.
天啊
Oh, god.
你们看 车!
Guys, the car!
-交给我 -天啊
- I got it! - Oh, my god.
我的天啊 不要
Oh, my god... no!
不
Oh, no.
你搞什么飞机啊 菲尔
What's the plan, Phil?!
好歹我有努力啊
At least I'm trying to do something!
爸爸 快下来
Dad, get off!
算了吧 菲尔
Come on, Phil!
让它去吧 放手吧
Let it go! Let it go!
我的天啊 亲爱的 松手吧
Oh, my god! Honey, let it go! Honey!
停下 停下
Stop, stop, stop.
不 不要啊...
Oh, no! That's not...
没事的
It's all right.
我还是…
I'm just...
还是实际点吧
I'm just being realistic,
看来我们得吐血甩卖了
but we're gonna need to lower the asking price.
嗨 宝贝
Hi, papi.
你这么快就回来了
You're here so soon.
我决定不去看电影了
I decided to skip the movie.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
还行
Yeah.
凯莉不喜欢我的西装
Kelly didn't like my jacket.
而且 她居然替我点菜
Plus, she ordered for me.
那她至少让你听了今日特色菜吧
Mm, did she let you hear the specials, at least?
没有 我不想和不懂我的人在一起
No. I don't want to be with someone who doesn't get me.
咱还有反式脂肪吗
Do we have any trans fats left?
当然啦
Of course.
况且 我还是更想和另一个女孩在一起
Besides, I think there's a girl I'd rather spend time with.
哎呀 你真是太乖鸟
Ohh, that's so sweet.
我是全世界最幸福的妈妈了
I'm the luckiest mother in the world.
我是曼尼 请问艾丽莎在吗
Hey. This is Manny. Is Alicia there?
艾丽莎是谁
Who's Alicia?
她和我一起上历史课
She's a girl in my history class.
我们要演示弗朗西斯·培根的六度空间
We like to play "six degrees of sir Francis Bacon."
你刚甩了一个女人
You just tossed a woman aside.
马上就钓上了另一个啦
Immediately you go to the next one?!
不 我只是...
No, I just...
只是 只是什么?!
Just... just what?!
你不能这样对待女人
This is not the way you treat women!
男人没有一个好东西
Men are all the same.
伤了女人的心后却一笑而过
They break women's hearts, and they don't care!
男人都是禽兽
Men are all animals!
亲爱的
Hey, honey.
禽兽
Animal!
销售的艺术就在于
The art of the sale is all about...
忽略该忽略的
what you leave out.
"83款经典车型"
"83 classic wagon."
其实配件老难找了
Tough to find parts.
"厂家以后都不生产了"
"They don't make them like this anymore."
其实是有安全隐患
For legal reasons.
"可供幸福大家庭享用多年"
"Enjoyed for many years by one happy family."
浣熊它们家
Of raccoons.
开玩笑的 其实
I'm kidding. Actually...
其实它的确带给我们一段很长的快乐时光
Actually, it did make us happy for a long time.
真的很难说再见
It's gonna be tough to say goodbye.
世事皆如此
It always is.
没人喜欢改变
Nobody loves change.
但是
But...
学会放手也是人生的一部分
Part of life is learning to let things go.
我真以为自己要吐你身上了
I totally thought I was gonna puke on you.
你真敢我就杀了你
I would have killed you if you did.
是哦 就像你杀了那只蜘蛛一样
Oh, yeah, like you killed that spider?
你又没看到 好大一只呢
Oh, you didn't see it. It was huge.
还记得妈妈座椅倒下去的时候
Remember the look on mom's face
她脸上的表情吗
when her seat fell down?
还有爸爸扑到车头上的时候
How about when dad jumped on the hood of the car?
"你搞什么飞机啊 菲尔"
"What's the plan, Phil?!"
米奇 莉莉
Mitch? Lily?
我们在这儿呢
Hey, we're in here!
小公主在她的城堡里呢
Princess is in her castle!
你们在里面呆多久了
How long have you guys been out here?
小卡 她就是玩不够
Ohh. Cam, she can't get enough.
我们在里面呆了两个小时了
We've been in here for like two hours.
这可是咱俩为她而建的
And we did this for her.
要我把你弄出来吗
Need me to get you out of there?
这东西太不安全了 小卡
This thing is not safe, Cam.
到城堡后面去
Move to the back of the castle.
我知道怎么做
Yeah, no. I know the drill.
这次别再把我扛出来了
No, don't carry me out this time.
我想这会让莉莉误会
I think it sends the wrong message to Lily.
邻居们围观得可高兴了
Well, the neighbors enjoy it.